Mohammed Abdulsalam

LinkedIn | GitHub | Codeforces

Location: Alexandria, Egypt Email: moha4mach@gmail.com | Mobile: +20 12 1165 0982

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

I am a highly skilled web developer with over 2 year of experience in HTML, CSS, Javascript, 1 year of experience in PHP, MySQL. I have knowledge of popular frameworks such as React, and Vue.js. I worked on several projects using native PHP and MySQL/MariaDB, and have experience designing REST APIs.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : PHP, SQL, Javascript, HTML, CSS, SCSS, TeX

Frameworks : React.js

Libraries : PHPUnit, PHP Spread Sheet, ECDSA, React Router, Styled Components, Socket.IO

Databases : MySQL, MariaDB, SQLlite

Methodoligies

Concepts : OOP, Regular Expressions, Accessibility (WCAG), REST, ERD Design, SRS Design

Dev Tools : Vim, Visual Studio Code, XDebug, Node, npm, Vite, Git, Github, Apache HTTP Server, Linux, cron,

Docker, Insomnia

EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer Volunteer

Jan 2023 - Present

UCCD KSU Remote – Kafrelsheikh, Kafrelsheikh, Egypt

- Designed and developed dynamic and responsive student management website using React.js
- Worked with REST APIs to retrieve and display data from backend

Vice Head of Web Development Committee

Sep 2022 - Apr 2023

Remote – Kafrelsheikh, Kafrelsheikh, Egypt

- Share knowledge and experience with my fellow members
- Make sure the plan is suitable for members
- Demonstrated critical topics in core Front End technologies, including SEO, and Accessibility, through number of sessions

Full Stack Developer Feb 2022 - Present

Freelance

GDSC KSU

- Design and development of websites using HTML, CSS, and Javascript
- Desing and development of back-ends using PHP, MYSQL/MariaDB
- Worked on REST APIs for medium-sized systems
- Analysis of stakeholders reuirements, and design ERD, SRS, and various documents
- Deployed and maintained websites on AWS EC2 linux server

EDUCATION

University of Kafrelsheikh - Faculty of Computers and Information

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 3.25/4

Kafrelsheikh, Kafrelsheikh, Egypt Sep 2020 - Jul 2024

Visualizing Sorting Algorithms

HTML, CSS, Javascript

Source Code

- Implemented different sorting algorithms in Javascript
- Used Asynchronous Programming using Javascript to visualize sorting
- Deployed on GitHub pages via GitHub Actions

UCCD Website React.js, Git Private

- Designed and developed a clean and modern website using HTML, CSS, and Javascript
- Utilized responsive design to ensure compatibility across all devices
- · Communicated with backend using a RESTful API

Monopoly Game

HTML, CSS, SCSS, Javascript

Source Code

- · Used ECMA Modules to reduce coupling
- Worked with CSS Grid and Flexbox to simplify complex design
- Deployed on GitHub pages via GitHub Actions

Salem Clinic Website

PHP, MySQL, Javascript, Git

Private

- Designed and developed dynamic monolith website using PHP, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Worked on admin panel providing article management, content management, and admins priviliges
- Developed Markup to HTML library using PHP, and Javascript, utilized in articles creation, editing, and viewing
- · Deployed using Apache server on AWS EC2 instance, with domain name and HTTPS certificate configured
- Used a **cronjob** to backup data periodically

Simple API Framework PHP Source Code

- Developed various utilities to facilitate **RESTful APIs** developing
- Implemented my own Router, and JWT utilities

Clinic Management System / ERP System

PHP, MariaDB, Socket.IO

Private

- A CRUD application exposed using a RESTful API made with PHP
- Analysed stakeholders requirements, deigned **ERD** based on this analysis
- Used XDebug to facilitate debugging process, and PHPUnit to automate unit testing
- Worked on many features that support bussiness logic, includes live queues, activity log, authorization rules and priviliges, payroll system, patient management system, etc...
- Used Socket.IO under Node.js to build socket server to maintain live queues data between clients